

Dr. Rebecca (Becky) SMETHURST



rebecca.smethurst @physics.ox.ac.uk



rebeccasmethurst.co.uk

0044 1865 273 640

Department of Astrophysics
Denys Wilkinson Building
Keble Road
Oxford
OX1 3RH
United Kingdom

I am a Junior Research Fellow (JRF) at Christ Church at the University of Oxford. My research focuses on the growth and effects of supermassive black holes on their host galaxies. I am a member of both the SDSS-IV MaNGA and Galaxy Zoo teams. I am also an enthusiastic science communicator posting weekly videos on my YouTube channel, 'Dr. Becky', which has over 380,000 subscribers. I have also written a popular public science book entitled 'Space: 10 Things You Should Know' which was named one of Sky at Night magazines Top 20 books of 2019.

Research Experience

October 2018 -

Junior Research Fellow: Searching for Observational Evidence of AGN Feedback Christ Church, University of Oxford

January 2017 - September 2018

Ogden Trust Research Fellow: Galaxy Evolution: Inside-out or Outside-In? University of Nottingham

October 2013 - January 2017:

The influence of morphology, AGN and environment on the quenching histories of galaxies.

Supervisor: Chris Lintott University of Oxford

October 2011 - June 2012:

Searching for TP-AGB star signatures in post-starburst ('E+A') galaxies:

Supervisors: Russell J. Smith, John Lucey Durham University, St. Aidan's College

Achievements & Prizes

Royal Astronomical Society Winton Award 2022 for research
Institute of Physics Mary Somerville Bronze Medal 2020
Caroline Herschel Lectureship Prize 2020
Royal Astronomical Society Group Prize 2019 - Galaxy Zoo Team
Vice Chancellor's Public Engagement with Research Award 2019 - 'Dr Becky'
Institute of Physics Early Career Physics Communicator Finalist, 2015
FameLab UK National Final 2014, Audience Winner & Judges Runner-up
Parent's Association Prize for Leadership, Bolton School Girls' Division, 2008
Prize for Achievement in Physics, Bolton School Girls' Division, 2008

Observing Experience

Observer at the Shane-3m at the Lick Observatory, California - 05/18
Remote observer with the Shane-3m at the Lick Observatory, California - 10/17
Observer at the CSO in Mauna Kea, Hawaii - 02/15
Remote observer, from Oxford, with the CSO in Mauna Kea, Hawaii - 11/14
Observer at the INT Spectrograph in La Palma, Canary Islands - 05/14

Conference Organisation

April 2019:

Lead organiser of SDSS-IV: MaNGA collaboration meeting, Oxford, UK

November 2017:

SOC member for .Astronomy 9, Cape Town, SA

July 2017:

SOC member of Galaxy Zoo Tenth Anniversary Conference, Oxford

June 2016

Head of SOC and LOC for . Astronomy 8, Oxford

Education

October 2013 - January 2017: DPhil, Pembroke College, University of Oxford Supervisor: Professor Chris Lintott

October 2008 - June 2012: MPhys, St. Aidan's College, University of Durham 1st class MPhys degree in Physics and Astronomy

September 1998 - August 2008: Bolton School Girls' Division A-Levels: Physics (A), Maths (A), Further Maths (A), Chemistry (A), General Studies (A)